<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<localisation>
    <string id="index_title">
        <![CDATA[rBiblia – a free program for browsing Bible translations]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_description">
        <![CDATA[rBiblia – your way to read the Bible]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_quick_access">
        <![CDATA[quickly access many Bible translations in different languages]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_easy_compare">
        <![CDATA[easily check the same verse in different translations]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_browse_them_all">
        <![CDATA[browse multiple translations at the same time]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_view_customisation">
        <![CDATA[change the default font color and size]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_repository_management">
        <![CDATA[simply download and remove translations within the program]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_clipboard_copy">
        <![CDATA[copy verses to the clipboard]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_bookmarks">
        <![CDATA[create complex bookmarks for chosen places in the translations]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_dictionary">
        <![CDATA[access a dictionary of Biblical terms]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_updates">
        <![CDATA[automatic program updates]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_you_rule">
        <![CDATA[work only with the translations you are interested in]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_low_requirements">
        <![CDATA[small size and low hardware requirements]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_multi_language">
        <![CDATA[support for different language versions (Polish, English and Russian by default)]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_features_available_for_free">
        <![CDATA[available for free :-)]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_legal_lead">
        <![CDATA[What about the legal status of the translations used in the program?]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_legal_note">
        <![CDATA[This is not an easy question, because on the one hand we are talking about "God's word" which we should preach to the whole world. On the other hand, gathering a group of experienced translators and the time devoted to preparing a high quality text are costly, and as the Bible says: "The laborer is worthy of his reward" [1 Timothy 5:18]. For this reason, I have decided to divide the translations into authorized ones (available legally, based on the author's assent or due to the expiration of copyright), and unauthorized ones, which have not been licensed by their publishers. During the work on the program I will attempt to obtain the assent to fully authorized use of these texts. Until that time I have decided to pass the moral question on to the users, who can decide for themselves if they want to install these translations on their computers (no translations are automatically bundled with the program).]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_latest_release">
        <![CDATA[The most recent versions of the program is: <version>]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_file_size">
        <![CDATA[Download size: <size>]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_link_download">
        <![CDATA[Download the program]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_requirements">
        <![CDATA[Hardware requirements]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_dotnet_requirements">
        <![CDATA[Any computer with a Windows operating system (XP till 11) and the .NET Framework 3.5/4 environment (available by default since Windows 7 – in case of an older system you need to install it from the <dotnet_start>developer's website<dotnet_end>). To download new translations you need an Internet connection. Installing and running the program <u>does not require</u> administrator rights.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_support_lead">
        <![CDATA[Support and program development]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_support_description">
        <![CDATA[If you've found an error in the program or have an idea for improvement, write to me. You can do it through the <contact_start>contact form<contact_end>.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_support_maintain">
        <![CDATA[I support and develop this program using my own means, because I'm eager to learn the word of God – just like you :-)]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_support_donate">
        <![CDATA[If you can make a <donation_start>small donation<donation_end> for the maintenance of the program or for one of the causes I collect for, I'll be very grateful.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="template_title">
        <![CDATA[Free program for browsing Bible translations]]>
    </string>
    <string id="template_help_translate">
        <![CDATA[Help me translate <website_start>this website<website_end> and <locales_start>other language resources<locales_end> for the program]]>
    </string>
    <string id="translations_title">
        <![CDATA[rBiblia – translations available in the program]]>
    </string>
    <string id="translations_description">
        <![CDATA[Translations available in the rBiblia repository]]>
    </string>
    <string id="translations_lead">
        <![CDATA[Translations available for download from the rBiblia repository:]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_legal_summary">
        <![CDATA[The repository currently contains <count> translations (<list_start>see the full list<list_end>).]]>
    </string>
    <string id="template_available_translations">
        <![CDATA[Available translations]]>
    </string>
    <string id="template_link_contact">
        <![CDATA[Contact]]>
    </string>
    <string id="dotnet_lead">
        <![CDATA[Your system requires .NET framework version <version>]]>
    </string>
    <string id="dotnet_fx45">
        <![CDATA[Since version 2.6, rBiblia requires .NET framework version 4.7.2 or newer. You have been redirected here because .NET is not installed on your computer. Download .NET from the <fx472_start>developer's website<fx472_end> and install it.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="dotnet_fx35">
        <![CDATA[If you are using Windows XP/Vista, you need to install the <arch_start>legacy version 2.5.2<arch_end> of rBiblia, which requires .NET 3.5. Download .NET framework version 3.5 from the <fx35_start>developer's website<fx35_end>.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_legacy_release">
        <![CDATA[If you're using/running <win>, you can download the legacy version <ver>, which requires <dotnet>.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_web_release">
        <![CDATA[Now you can also enjoy basic functionality of the program in your web browser.]]>
    </string>
    <string id="index_link_web">
        <![CDATA[Show on-line version]]>
    </string>
</localisation>
